# **AYANDA FOLASHADE MOJISOLA (NEE OLADIRAN)**

Zone C3 House 6, Woru Area,Okinni, Osun State Mobile Tel: **08069213246** 

E-mail: folash007@yahoo.com

### **SUMMARY**

I am a germane being endowed with the heart of love, care and sacrifice.

A graduate of Electrical Electronics Engineering (power option) who understands the Operations of a Transmission station. As a youth corp I tutored students for a debate competition organized in the LGA where I served and we won the gold medal. This feat spurred the school to set up its first physics laboratory. The achievement also gave rise to doubling of the students' population in the school. I have also successfully coordinated a mentoring/self-empowerment program scheme which helped eradicate teenage pregnancy from 75% high to as low as 20% and helped reduced early marriage. In 2015, I helped prepare a student for English competition who came out as a silver medalist in the state.

### **PERSONAL DATA**

Home Town: Ipetu Ijesa Sex: Female Marital Status: Married

### **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

2021. PGD in Education - University of Ilorin (Nigerian Institute of Teachers, Kaduna)

2017 M. Sc. in Electrical Electronics Engineering (Power Option) – University Of Lagos, Akoka, Lagos.

**2010 B. Sc. (Hons) Electrical Electronics Engineering** - *Olabisi Onabanjo University, Ogun State, Nigeria.* 

**2001** West Africa Senior School Certificate – Nov – Dec G.C.E

**2002** West Africa Senior School Certificate – African Church Model Church, Ifako Ijaiye, Agege, Lagos.

**2002** National Examination Council – African Church Model Church, Ifako Ijaiye, Agege, Lagos.

1996 Primary School Leaving Certificate - Oluwole Christ the king School, Ejiqbo, Lagos.

# TRAINING /WORKSHOP/SEMINARS ATTENDED

Training: Data Processing/Information Technology

Organizer: Trendafrique International Institute of Computer Technology - FCT Abuja

Venue: Osun State Ministry of Education

**Position**: Public School teacher

Date: May 2021

**Training**: 21st Century learning Design

Organizer: Segun Aina Foundation in partner with Osun State Ministry of Education

**Venue**: Osogbo Grammar School, Osun State **Position**: Science teacher representative

**Date:** February 2021

**Training**: Syllabus upgrade in Mathematics

Organizer: Osun State Ministry of Education

Venue: Moremi High School, Ile Ife Osun State

**Position**: Mathematics Teacher

Date: March 2018

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

August 2018 - till date: (Teaching staff) Osun State Civil Service Commission, SUBEB

Oroki High School, Agunbelewo, Osun state Designation:- Class and subject teacher

### Responsibility/Experience:

- I pursue relevant opportunities to grow professionally and keep up-to-date about the current knowledge and research in the subject area
- I plan and prepare appropriately the assigned courses and lectures for the subjects Mathematics and Physics
- I conduct assigned classes at the scheduled times and implement the designated curriculum completely and in due time
- I design and implement effective strategies to develop self-responsible/independent learners
- I provide opportunities for students to apply and practice what is learned
- I maintain a safe, orderly environment conducive to learning
- I comply with requirements for the safety and supervision of students inside and outside the classroom
- I assign reasonable assignments and homework to students as per school rules
- I evaluate students' performances in an objective, fair and timely manner
- I record and report timely the results of quizzes, tests, assignments, mid- and final term exams
- I comply with policies, standards, rules, regulations and procedures of the school
- I demonstrate timeliness and attendance for assigned responsibilities
- I work collaboratively with other professionals and staff
- I demonstrate the ability to perform teaching or other responsibilities, including good work habits, reliability, punctuality and follow-through on commitments
- I model a caring attitude and promote positive inter-personal relationships
- I foster and promote empathy, compassion and respect for the gender, ethnic, religious, cultural and learning diversity of students and staff included
- As a member of Examination and Timetable committee, I take part in school timetable preparation, vet school examination questions and do subject allocation to teachers
- Being part of the literary and debate committee, I coordinate inter and intra class debate competitions, prepare students for inter school debate and other related competitions
- In the lesson committee, I participate in lesson timetable preparation, coordinate students and teachers for the afternoon lessons and keep records of teachers and students attendance of same
- Science Teacher Representative
- I represent my school's science department in seminars and also the school's Local Govt. teachers at the ministry of education level at various meetings with stakeholders
- As the school's Social committee secretary, I take minutes of meetings, handle logistics for outings and staff welfare

October 2013 - August 2018: (Teaching staff) Osun State Civil Service Commission, SUBEB

Apara Memorial High School, Atakunmosa West, Osun state

Designation:- Class and subject teacher

### Responsibility/Experience:

- Was a class teacher and subject teacher
- Took responsibility for the monitoring of all Students (mentor and Mentee scheme)
- Maintained the teacher's dairy regularly with the lesson plan
- Attended the morning assembly, reach the class on time and follow the conduct rules
- Had meetings with parents to keep them informed and guide them about the progress of their ward/wards
- Encouraged students to develop reading habits and also participate in quiz
- Tutored and prepared students for both internal and external competition

- Mentored students by addressing them on morals principles, social and environment issues
- Evaluated the students from time to time
- As the School secretary, I conducted meetings, took minutes and also discussed the methods to improve the performance of students, teaching staffs and the school
- Was responsible for handling logistics for any outing

### September 2012 to January, 2013:

GOF international college, Onward Estate, Osogbo, Osun State

Designation:- Class and subject teacher

#### Responsibility/Experience:

- Maintained the teacher's dairy regularly with the lesson plan
- Attended the morning assembly, reach the class on time and follows the conduct rules
- Took responsibility for the monitoring of all Students
- Encouraged students to develop reading habits and also participate in quiz
- Tutored and prepared students for both internal and external competition
- Mentored students by addressing them on morals principles, social and environment issues
- Evaluated the students from time to time
- Carried out routine checks on students in the hostel to ensure their notes are well written, submitted and marked

### June 2011 to June, 2012: National service year

St. John's College Mutum Biyu, Gassol, Taraba State

Designation: - Class and subject teacher

### Responsibility/Experience:

- Took responsibility for the monitoring of all Students (mentor and Mentee scheme)
- Maintained the teacher's dairy regularly with daily lesson plan
- Always wrote and compiled detailed weekly lesson note
- Attended the morning assembly, reach the class on time and follows the conduct rules
- Had meetings with parents to keep them informed and guide them about the progress of their ward/wards
- Encouraged students to develop reading habits and also participate in quiz
- Tutored and prepared students for both internal and external competition
- Mentored students by addressing them on morals principles, social and environment issues
- Evaluated the students from time to time

### January 2009 to June, 2009:

Arkpack Int'l Nigeria Limited, lagos

Designation: - Industrial training

# Responsibility/Experience:

- Rewound and installed several induction motors
- Rewound and installed alternators
- Installed lightning arresters and carried out earthing of equipment
- Engaged in the purchase and sale of various electrical gargets
- Took part in the maintenance and repair of generators

#### October 2005 to December, 2005:

Power Holding Company of Nigeria PLC Sub Regional Transmission station, Ikeja West, Ayobo, Lagos Designation: - Industrial training

### Responsibility/Experience:

- Took hourly reading of all sub transmission stations in the operations department
- Took hourly reading of transformers in the switch yard

- Monitored the frequency meter
- Carried out load shedding to avoid system collapse
- Performed regular checks on the battery banks
- Carried out routine maintenance on isolators and circuit breakers
- Did routine checks on transformers in the switch yard
- Changed/Repaired faulty transformer fans in sub transmission stations
- Changed and topped transformer oil
- Ensured power stability for special assignments
- Was responsible for the collation of data from other sub transmission stations
- Engaged in the correction of errors/faults on circuit breakers
- Carried out replacement of faulty circuit breakers
- Repaired and took part in the connection of faulty power (sub transmission) cable

#### October 2003 to July, 2005:

Defaoo Nursery and Primary School, Ejigbo, Lagos Designation: - Stock keeper, auditor and assistant class teacher

#### Experience:

- Was in charge of customer care services on uniforms, books and Stationaries
- Was an assistant to the class teacher
- Performed accurate keeping of records
- Class minder
- Attended the morning assembly, reached the class on time and followed the conduct rules
- Had meetings with parents to keep them informed and guide them about the progress of their ward/wards
- Encouraged students to develop reading habits and also participate in quiz

# **VOLUNTEERING**

### May 2020 till date:

Excellence Community Education Welfare Scheme (ECEWS), Osun State Chapter, Nigeria. Contact: Mr. Femi Oyinbo, State Lead. +234 703 677 0470

Designation:- Program Assistant (Part Time)

# Responsibility/Experience:

- I carry out data analysis for every project location to allow for sectioning
- I disburse relief funds from government to locals according to individual status and vulnerability
- I involve in changing public opinion and raising awareness of emerging infectious diseases and pandemic response especially among the aged in various local governments
- I train individuals and groups to be empowered through learning of trades to help them take meaningful actions in their personal sphere or community
- I enlighten locals about nutrition with respect to age
- I monitor clients for social and behavior changes by developing communication strategies to provide positive results
- I take part in enlightenment campaign on tuberculosis and malaria at every location
- I engage the youth and young adults in the communities in mentoring sessions.

# **SKILLS**

- Hardworking and assertive
- Excellent listening skills
- Ability to work under minimum supervision
- Efficient organizational and team playing skills

- Efficient and adaptable with excellent communication skills (English and Yoruba)
- Excellent human relations and creative planning skill
- Proficient in the use of microsoft office packages

# **OBJECTIVES**

- To use my acquired knowledge in the development of my country
- To use my skills and training to better the lives of people around me
- To be actively involved in charity work within and beyond my immediate environment
- To lay a foundation of truth and transparency for people to emulate
- To use my God given abilities to help achieve my institution's aims and objectives

# **RESEARCH PROJECTS**

- Analysis of Electricity consumption pattern in selected teaching hospitals in Nigeria (2017)
- Junior Secondary School Students Performances as a Determinant of Selection into Science Classes in Senior Secondary school in olorunda LGA, Osun state, Nigeria (2021)

# **REFERENCES**

1. Dr. C.B. Adeosun

Snr. Lecturer at the department of Microbiology Redeemer University, Akoda Ede, Osun state.

Email:- adeosuncharles@yahoo.co.uk

Tel:- 08030690243

2. Omowumi O. Komolafe Esq

Head of litigation, B.E.I. Nwofor & Co.

57A Emekuku str, D/line, Port Harcourt, Rivers State.

Email:- omowumikomolafe@gmail.com

Tel:- 08023914407

3. Professor Jelil Oguntola Alamu Head of department, Mechanical Engineering Osun State University, Oke Baale, Osogbo, Osun State Email:-

<u>Tel:-</u> 08033858298